MUHAMMAD TAHA

in: MUHAMMADTAHANASIR

: MUHAMMADTAHANASIR | m.tahanasir.cs@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm currently a Sophomore at FAST NUCES studying Computer Science. I've built a strong coding base and get the ins and outs of object-oriented programming (OOP). I've also got handson experience with Python. I've faced some tough spots in my studies, but I've pushed through them. This has made me tough and focused.

WORK HISTORY

TECHNOHACKS EDUTECH OFFICIAL

Python Developer Intern | TechnoHacks EduTech Official, Nashik | October 2023 - January 2024

• During this internship, I gained valuable insights into Python programming, which improved my problem-solving skills. Additionally, I completed several small projects during this internship, which provided me with a deeper understanding of programming in Python, honed my skills, and expanded my knowledge.

CODSOFT

Python Programming Intern | CodSoft, West Bengal | September 2023 - October 2023

- During my CodSoft Python Programming Internship, I gained valuable insights into various aspects of Python programming. I learned how to apply Python to real-world scenarios, enhancing my problem-solving skills.
- In addition to these core learnings, this facet of the internship imparted a comprehensive understanding of how to proficiently push projects to GitHub and navigate the various functionalities of this essential platform.
- Overall, the internship enriched my Python programming knowledge, honed my practical skills, and provided me with a deeper understanding of programming in Python.

SKILLS

- Python
- C, C++
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Abode Lightroom, Illustrator, Photoshop
- Flutter, Dart

EDUCATION

DEGREE OBTAINED (BCSC)

FAST- National University of Computer & Emerging Sciences 2023 – current

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Software Engineering Professional

NED Academy - NED University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi

Credential ID: 19073 Show Credential

Career Essentials in Generative AI by Microsoft and LinkedIn Microsoft **Show Credential**

Object Oriented Programming SpecializationGoldsmiths, University of London
Credential ID: 8NFMPTN5H4SM Show Credential